<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Andy An's blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[A blog written by an average engineer]]></description><link>https://andyan.dev</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 11:14:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Why blogs?]]></title><description><![CDATA[As I am typing the first sentence of my first blog ever, I still cannot believe it that I am doing something I absolutely hated when I was…]]></description><link>https://andyan.dev/why-blogs/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://andyan.dev/why-blogs/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As I am typing the first sentence of my first blog ever, I still cannot believe it that I am doing something I absolutely hated when I was young. Writing was never my thing and I sucked at it. Maybe there was too much pressure and the goal was too clear - getting a good score to make your parents proud. That 600 or 800 words requirement was my worst nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time I considered writing blogs was 3 years ago. I even set up a WordPress website and bought a domain on Bluehost. It was stupid that I paid that much money for a CMS with many fancy features only few of which are actually useful for me. I did not know what I was doing and I did not even publish one blog with it as I lost interests. Nowadays I would much prefer a minimal site but with great extensibility and most importantly, as cheap as possible. I guess that is because skills and knowledge give me the freedom or ability to do it in the exact way I want and same with many other things. It also saves A LOT of money. (Running a site like this is almost for free. Just need to pay for a domain such as &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;andyan.dev&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later I may reflect on things that I often think about but never had a chance to talk about, write about memorable time I spent with other people, or some technology I am interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I will add a comment section later. Maybe also a dark theme switcher. Maybe…&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>